人人影視傾情奉獻
翻譯  小飯
翻譯  珈美
翻譯  癢癢惦記小跟班
翻譯  江湖人稱王姑娘
翻譯  沫沫
翻譯  丶Charl
翻譯  杏仁斯嘉麗
時間軸  吉吉
后期  餓得慌
校對  草草
總監  草草
紙牌屋
第四季  第十集
"她與佩特羅夫單獨較量
"She squared off mano-a-mano with Petrov
敲定了救市協議
to finalize the bailout deal.
與此同時  杜蘭特國務卿則無所事事地等候
Meanwhile, Secretary Durant twiddled her thumbs, waiting
連上談判桌的資格都沒有"
without a seat at the bargaining table."
很瘋狂  對吧
Pretty wild, huh?
-什么時候發的  -凌晨三點
- When was that posted? -3:00 A.M.
你該走了
You should go.
-早餐都不給嗎  -我要工作了
- No breakfast, even? - I have work to do.
歡迎回來  這是戲劇性的一天
Welcome back. It's a dramatic day.
我們看下現在情況
Let's see where things stand.
沃爾夫  可以看到形式大變
And, Wolf, you can see the big change.
凱瑟琳·杜蘭特現在上了我們的總統提名墻
Catherine Durant now on our presidential nominating wall.
弗蘭西斯·安德伍德
希瑟·鄧巴
凱瑟琳·杜蘭特
涉及到的超級代表
希瑟·鄧巴
弗蘭西斯·安德伍德
原本有望成為副總統的她
She has shifted from vice presidential hopeful
轉而競爭總統候選人
to potential presidential candidate.
杜蘭特成為候選人或許對那些對安德伍德
And a Durant candidacy might be appealing to Democrats
和鄧巴都沒興趣的民主黨人很有吸引力
who aren't enthusiastic about either Underwood or Dunbar.
設想一下
And imagine this scenario
縱觀整個大會的大局
if we play this out through this convention.
希瑟·鄧巴退出初選時支持率是46%
Heather Dunbar came out of the primaries, of course, with 46%.
這還不足以贏得提名
It's not enough to win the nomination,
但如果安德伍德總統要取勝
but for him to win, President Underwood,
他還需要這些超級代表
he still needs these superdelegates.
鄧巴退出時他贏得了選民票
He won the popular vote when Dunbar withdrew,
但你的意思是他還沒有取得絕對多數
but you're saying he doesn't have a technical majority.
659名超級代表尚未投票
659 superdelegates yet to weigh in,
所以弗蘭克·安德伍德已經掉到了48%
so you see Frank Underwood drops down to 48%.
他依然領先  但還不足以獲得提名
He's still in the lead, but not enough to clinch the nomination.
想聽更復雜的嗎  好像還不夠復雜似的
And you want a little bit more intrigue, like we need that?
24個州  沃爾夫  標亮的這24個州
Twenty-four states, Wolf, these 24 states highlighted,
沒有所謂的不忠代表法
they do not have so-called faithless delegate laws,
也就是說這24個州的代表沒必要
meaning in these 24 states, the delegates don't have to,
法律上沒有規定他們必須投票給
they are not legally bound to vote for the candidate
贏得本州初選或黨團會議的候選人
who won their state's primary or caucus.
他們可以隨心所欲投給任何人
They can vote for whoever they want.
他們可以投給希瑟·鄧巴
They could vote for Heather Dunbar.
他們可以轉投給凱瑟琳·杜蘭特
They could switch over and vote for Catherine Durant.
沃爾夫  如果他們想的話  還可以投給你
Wolf, if they want, they could vote for you.
他們不會投給我的
So... They're not gonna vote for me.
但如果杜蘭特國務卿吸走了足夠的選票
But if Secretary Durant siphons off enough votes
或是安德伍德未能在初輪投票中獲得多數
or Underwood doesn't get that majority in the first ballot,
那就一切皆有可能了嗎
what, all bets are off?
我覺得今天唯一可以肯定的是
I think about the only sure bet today is
安德伍德總統一定恨不得
President Underwood must be wishing
當初沒有同意召開開放黨代會
he hadn't agreed to this open convention.
杜蘭特或是鄧巴真的有可能取勝嗎
Does Durant or Dunbar really have a shot at winning this thing?
當然  現任總統本就不是獲選上臺的
Sure. You've got a president who wasn't elected to begin with.
他的健康狀況現在也是一個大問號
His health is a giant question mark right now.
他這個任期非常艱難  再加上開放黨代會
He's had a rocky tenure, plus you've got an open convention.
一切皆有可能
Anything could happen.
比如杜蘭特成為勁敵
Like giving, uh, Durant a run for her money.
順便提一下  頭條網
Uh, Slugline, by the way,
轉載了昨天政治新聞網的報道
picked up the Politico story from yesterday.
在選舉現場可能會引起一定注意
It could get traction out there on the floor.
沒錯  而且在開放黨代會上
That's true, and, again, at an open convention,
克萊爾·安德伍德也許會突然成為黑馬
Claire Underwood may suddenly be the dark horse here.
母親
Mother.
你好啊  克萊爾
Hello, Claire.
你怎么搬到樓下了
Why'd you move down here?
臨終關懷的護士說我不該再上下樓梯了
Hospice lady said I shouldn't be going up and down stairs anymore.
而且我也喜歡這里  光線更充足
Besides, I like it. More light.
那是誰
Who's that?
湯姆  能讓我們單獨聊聊嗎
Uh, Tom, would you give us a minute, please?
抱歉
Sorry.
不不  過來  小伙子
No, no. Come here, young man.
您好  黑爾太太
Hi, Mrs. Hale.
我叫湯姆
My name's Tom.
托馬斯·耶茨  小說家  你應該聽說過他
It's Thomas Yates, the novelist. You've probably heard of him.
我覺得從約翰·契弗起就沒什么值得讀的書了
I think everything since John Cheever isn't worth readin'.
您也許是對的
You're probably right.
克萊爾
Well, Claire...
你是來清點
did you come to take stock of
我死后你要繼承的遺產嗎
everything you're gonna inherit when I die?
很方便  不是嗎
Well, it's convenient, isn't it,
有個瀕死的母親  可以拿來做出城的理由
having a dying mother when you need an excuse to skip town?
我們不會打擾你的
We won't disturb you.
認識您很高興  黑爾太太
It was nice meeting you, Mrs. Hale.
-叫我伊麗莎白  -好  那您也叫我湯姆
- Elizabeth. - All right. Well, then you call me Tom.
我討厭人叫我托馬斯
I hate "Thomas."
-好  湯姆  -就這么說定了
- Fair enough, Tom. - We have a deal.
我們需要黨內團結  而不是四分五裂
We want a unified party, not a fractured one.
我不能在規則上反復無常
I can't play fast and loose with the rules.
這是開放黨代會  本就沒有規則
This is an open convention. There are no rules.
我已經按你的意思把黃金時段給了希爾議員
I already gave Senator Sheer that prime-time spot that you wanted.
但這事  作為黨代會主席
But this, as chair of the convention--
是我讓你做黨代會主席的
And I made you chair of this convention
就是想防備這種事
precisely for moments like this.
我有義務不徇私
I have an obligation to not play favorites.
你對黨的義務
Your obligation to the party
就是對黨領袖的義務
is an obligation to the leader of the party,
身為總統  我就是黨領袖
and as the president, that would be me.
-沒錯吧  -是的  先生  但是
- Correct? - Yes, sir, but--
那這就無關徇私  而是黨內團結
Then this isn't about favoritism. It's about solidarity.
我們已為您安排好車
We've got a car waiting to take you
帶您去會場了  惠特克女士
to the convention hall, Ms. Whittaker.
我應民主黨全國委員會
I call this convention to order
以及黨代會主席  帕特·惠特克之命
of the Democratic National Committee
宣布會議開始
and the convention chair, Patti Whittaker.
早上好
Good morning.
我剛得知  總統要去華盛頓
I was just informed that the president will travel to Washington
會見國家安全小組
to meet with his national security team.
鑒于兩項提名的主要競爭者
Given that key contenders for both slots on the ticket
今天都不能到場
aren't able to be on the floor today,
規則委員會建議
the Rules Committee has advised that
我們等他們回來
we should wait for their return
再進行下一輪投票
before any further votes are held.
現有一項動議  延期所有投票
There is a motion to postpone all votes
直到總統回來
until the president's return.
哈里發國已于昨晚深夜從蘇瓦爾出發
ICO began its advance from As Suwar late last night,
據我們的計算和他們目前的行軍速度來看
and by our calculations and their current pace,
我們預計他們會在72小時內到達幼發拉底河
we expect them to reach the Euphrates within 72 hours.
這可能影響公路和河道交通
Now, this could disrupt highway and river traffic,
但更重要的是
but more importantly,
這會使他們有機會
could give them the opportunity
破壞該地區的重要水壩
to destroy vital dams in the region.
因此  我現在就前往華盛頓
And as a result, I am heading to Washington right now
來討論怎樣阻止這次哈里發國的進軍
so that we can decide exactly how we should stop this ICO advance.
這突然的計劃變動
Is this sudden change of plans
是您昨天與康威州長會晤的結果嗎
a result of your meeting with Governor Conway yesterday?
如果州長的言論促使哈里發國加速計劃
Well, it wouldn't surprise me if ICO accelerated their plans,
我也不會驚奇
uh, because of the governor's comments.
他們懂得如何利用媒體的關注
They certainly know how to take advantage of media attention.
但無論事實是否如此
But whether that's the truth or not,
解決這個威脅迫在眉睫
this is an imminent threat which we must deal with immediately.
我很高興總統聽取我的意見
I'm glad the president heard me
并終于采納了布洛哈特將軍的建議
and finally took General Brockhart's advice to heart.
現在我們只能
Now we'll just have to
等著看看是否真能得到什么結果
wait and see if it actually results in anything.
只希望不會收效太小  太遲
I just hope it's not too little, too late.
州長先生  您現在如何打算  留在亞特蘭大嗎
What are your plans now, Governor? Remain in Atlanta?
不  我和漢娜要回到競選活動中
No, Hannah and I are heading back on the trail.
我們在佐治亞州完成了我們要做的事
We accomplished what we needed to here in Georgia, and
我們今天要去亞利桑那州  然后去猶他州
we're heading off to Arizona today and then Utah.
總統先生  總統先生
Mr. President. Mr. President.
為什么去華盛頓  而不是在這里解決
Why Washington and not here?
這個問題太敏感  不能在外解決
This issue is too sensitive for a mobile White House.
我需要在戰況室里
I need to be in the Situation Room
與行政人員和顧問團隊一起討論
with my entire staff and team of advisors around me.
總統先生  總統先生
Mr. President. Mr. President.
亞當
Yes, Adam.
總統先生  這是為了堵國務卿杜蘭特的嘴嗎
Mr. President, is this a way to silence Secretary Durant
因為路易斯安那州將她推入了總統競選
after Louisiana put her in the running for president?
我不會把國家安全與政治競爭混為一談
I don't use national security matters for political purposes.
你知道的  亞當
You know that, Adam.
如果你們還有其它問題  請向賽斯提問
You have any other further questions, please direct them to Seth.
非常感謝各位
Thank you all very much.
-要我一起去嗎  -不  你留下
- You want me to come with? - No, you stay behind.
-掌控好局面  -是  先生
- Keep everything under control. - Yes, sir.
有消息稱她已經離開亞特蘭大了
There are reports that she's left Atlanta.
第一夫人是今早早些時候離開的
The First Lady left earlier this morning.
她母親的健康狀況在過去幾天進一步惡化了
Her mother's health has deteriorated in the past few days.
亞當
Adam.
這是否意味著她會退出副總統的競選
Does this mean she's out of the running for VP?
第一夫人從來就沒參選過
The First Lady was never in the running.
她和總統會繼續支持凱瑟琳·杜蘭特
She and the president continue to support Catherine Durant--
四個孩子的父親  水手
Father of four, sailor...
因為踩到了生銹的魚鉤導致葡萄球菌感染
staph infection from stepping on a rusty fish hook.
天吶
Heavens!
還有這個  嗯  你曾是只果蠅
And this one, yeah, you were a fruit fly.
-果蠅  -對
- A fruit fly. - Yes.
你曾是拉斯普京的伴侶  享用他14英寸的
You were a consort to Rasputin and his 14-inch...
俄帝國時期神棍
因為尺寸大而聞名
實為11英寸
不要  別說出來
No, don't say it.
我不用說  你已經在腦補了
I don't have to say it because you're already imagining it.
我看完了
I looked it over.
咱們出去談
I'll meet you outside.
打算留給薇和那些姑娘們的
Uh, gonna leave all this to Vi and the girls
如果你不想要的話
if you're not interested.
外婆的首飾
Grandmother's jewelry?
要是我不至少跟你提一嘴
She'd turn over in her grave
她在墓里都得氣得翻身
if I didn't at least offer it to you.
她品味真不錯
She had great taste.
不然你以為我的品味從哪來的
Where do you think I got it from?
這是什么
What's this?
打開看看吧
Look at it. Open it up.
肯定還是值點錢的  第一夫人的乳牙
Must be worth somethin', baby teeth of the First Lady.
我挺喜歡那個小伙兒
I like that boy.
能逗我笑
Makes me laugh.
就像你父親在世時那樣
Like your father used to.
我想象不出爸爸扮成算命的是什么樣
Can't imagine daddy dressed up as a fortune teller.
你會意想不到的  他也有逗逼的一面
Oh, you'd be surprised. He had a silly side to him.
我是沒見過
Not that I ever saw.
有些事他只會在我面前做
Well, there were certain things that he only did with me.
你瞧  笑一笑能緩解疼痛
Oh, you see, laughter is good for the pain.
比嗎啡還有效
Even better than this morphine.
-我來幫你吧  -不用  我自己能行
- Let me help you. - No, no, I can do it.
你走吧
You just go.
走
Go!
你把所有內容都劃掉了
You crossed everything out.
-因為不夠好  -我知道
- It wasn't good. - I know.
等她去世了  你打算對這里也那樣嗎
Is that what you're gonna do here, after she dies?
因為不夠好  把一切都抹去
Cross everything out... because it wasn't good?
我不會和你談論我母親的
You're not going to get me to talk about my mother.
我希望不會
I hope not.
恨太丑惡了
Hatred's ugly.
天氣這么好  不適合談那個
It's too beautiful a day for that.
回去干活兒嘍
Back to the salt mines.
請坐
Please, sit.
先生  這是哈里發國目前的位置
Sir, these are the current ICO positions.
我們還在起草任務項目
We're still drafting action items,
但是我們可給您一個大致的
but we can give you a rough sense--
在討論軍事選擇之前
Well, before we discuss any military options,
我要和大馬士革通話  看看他們能允許什么行動
I'd like to put a call in to Damascus and see what they'll allow.
國務卿女士  跟我一起來吧
Madam Secretary, won't you join me?
為了單獨見我  你不惜召集
So you had to call a national security meeting
國家安全會議
just to get us in the same room?
也為了不讓你和康威通話
And to keep you off the phone with Conway.
我只需要給他打一通電話  不需要第二通
All I needed was one call to him. I don't need to make another.
你不是真覺得他會任命你為國務卿吧
You don't actually think he's gonna make you Secretary of State, do you?
估計不會  但我真想看到
Probably not, but I would've paid good money
他告訴你消息時你的臉色
just to see your face when he told you.
我從沒保證會和你一起參選
I never promised you the ticket.
我只說了會盡力
I promised you I'd try.
你是裝作盡力
You pretended to try.
對克萊爾的支持不會憑空出現
Claire's support didn't just happen on its own,
你還好意思握著我的手
and you had the gall to take my hand,
看著我的眼睛  對我撒謊
look me in the eye and lie to my face.
-你錯了  凱茜  -拜托  弗蘭克
- You're mistaken, Cathy. - Oh, come on, Frank.
從沃克就職的那天起
I've had a front row seat to everything
我就近距離看到了一切
since the day Walker took office,
所有的謊言和背叛  我還幫了你
all the lies and betrayals, and I helped you.
我的錯誤是以為你不會在背后捅我一刀
My mistake was I assumed you wouldn't stab me in the back.
你的錯誤是弄巧成拙
Your mistake is that it backfired.
這完全是個人恩怨  對吧
This is all personal, isn't it?
完全是為了報復我在醫院時  克萊爾那樣對你
This is about how Claire treated you when I was in the hospital.
別這么小瞧我  這是生意
Give me more credit than that. This is business.
我們曾是合作伙伴  是你違約了
We were partners. You broke the contract.
-那你想要什么  -還有什么呢  弗蘭克
- So, what do you want? - What else is there, Frank?
什么都沒了
Nothing.
很簡單  要么讓克萊爾的票改投給我
It's simple. Either Claire's votes come my way...
要么我就把大會搞得一團亂
or I turn the convention upside down.
我們得談談賽斯
We need to talk about Seth.
我接到了許多前客戶的電話
I've been getting calls from former clients.
你開口之前  我告訴你我干過的壞事吧
Now, before you say anything, here's the dirt.
我8年級時在一次數學測驗上做過弊
I cheated on a math test in 8th grade,
我16歲時曾為返校節偷過一條裙子
I shoplifted a homecoming dress when I was 16,
我大一時跟一個女生聯誼會的姐妹搞過
I experimented with a sorority sister in freshman year,
我2007年晚交了稅
and I was late on my taxes in 2007.
但他不會找到任何開除我的正當理由
What he won't find is anything that justifies firing me.
他肯定只是在審查你  我們對每個人都要審查
I'm sure he was just vetting you. We do that with everyone.
你非要這樣說的話  那好吧
Okay, if that's your story, then fine,
但我只在乎贏得大選
but all I care about is winning this election.
我們放下個人恩怨  團結合作  好嗎
So let's get past our personal shit and be a team, okay?
我們在對抗同一個敵人  總統先生
We're fighting a common enemy here, Mr. President.
我們保持團結十分重要
It's important that we remain united.
嗯  我向你保證我們采取任何行動前
Yeah, and I can assure you that Secretary Durant will reach out
杜蘭特國務卿都會跟你聯系
before we conduct any operation.
非常感謝  總統先生
Thank you for your time, Mr. President.
我們一想出計劃就會聯系你
We'll be in touch as soon as we come up with a plan.
你一副我還能當國務卿的樣子
You're acting like I'll still be Secretary of State.
如果你決策正確  就會是的
Well, if you play your cards right, you will be.
你還請過誰當你的副總統
Who else did you offer the VP slot to?
杰姬  奧斯汀  我  還有誰
There's Jackie, Austen, me. Anyone else?
奧斯汀自愿退出的  杰姬也是
Austen withdrew on his own, and so did Jackie.
我沒有逼她退出
I did not push her out.
杰姬說你毫不尊重她
Jackie says you took her for granted,
說你威脅她  恐嚇她
that you bullied her, you intimidated her.
她正在給加州的代表們
And that is what she is telling every member
一個一個打電話說這番話
of the California delegation, one phone call at a time.
加州  票很多
California. Lots of votes.
加州  民主黨大會最大的票倉
California, the largest piece of delegates at the Democratic Convention.
我聽說代表團正在傾向希瑟·鄧巴
I'm told that delegation is trending toward Heather Dunbar.
來看一下  沃爾夫
Let's watch this, Wolf.
想像一下她只拿下
Let's imagine she only picked up
加州三分之二的代表
two-thirds of the California delegates.
這就超過300票了
That gets you above 300 there.
另外  我們估計她能守住她家鄉康涅狄格州
Plus, we assume she'll keep her home state Connecticut's support.
這樣起點就相當不錯
Off to a pretty good start.
超過300張代表票  大概是7%的選票了
It's over 300 delegates. What, roughly, uh, 7% of the vote?
單單這些就足以使投票進入第二輪了吧
That alone could take this, what, to a second ballot?
沒錯  又是開放黨代會
That takes it to a second ballot, an open convention again.
而且我們預計
Plus, we also assume that
路易斯安那州會繼續支持凱瑟琳·杜蘭特
Louisiana will stay with Catherine Durant.
至少在第一輪投票結束前
So, we are not going to have a definitive idea
我們無法確切估計
of how all this is gonna shape up
局勢將如何走向
at least until they conduct the first ballot.
目前總統和杜蘭特國務卿
There's still no update as to, uh,
將何時返回尚無新消息
when the president and Secretary Durant will return.
是啊  這也增加了不確定性
No, and that adds to some of the uncertainty here.
我們回到現場  看看情況如何
So let's go back to the floor, see how things are playing out.
文章里沒有說明
It didn't specify in the article
當時車隊是朝哪個方向開的
which direction the motorcade was heading.
朝東
East.
貝茨城
東
你確定嗎
You're sure?
非常感謝
Thank you very much.
密蘇里州  貝茨城
阿道希保留區
貝茨城葡萄園
不是
堪薩斯城
我去
Hot damn!
我保證你想當多久國務卿都可以
I am promising you Secretary of State for as long as you want it
你2024年競選總統時我會全力支持
and my full support when you run for President in 2024.
誰知道呢  你說不好會走運
I mean, who knows, you might even get lucky.
我的肝臟或許在那之前就衰竭了
My liver might fail before then.
你把我的職位許給貝克的時候
Your promises stopped meaning much
你的承諾就沒有意義了
after you promised Baker my job.
我完全沒打算讓他當國務卿
I have no intention of offering him Secretary of State.
那么你就像沃克騙你一樣騙了他
Oh, so you lied to him the way Walker lied to you.
不  我和沃克又不是老交情
No. Walker and I didn't have a history.
沃克也不尊重我
And Walker didn't respect me.
你我是有交情的  凱茜  我也非常尊重你
You and I have a history, Cathy, and I respect you immensely.
但是我們共事才3年
But our history goes back three years.
克萊爾和我已經是30年的搭檔了
Claire's and my partnership goes back 30.
你必須尊重這一點
You have to respect that.
我可能會...
I might have...
如果你一開始就對我說實話的話
if you had been honest with me from the beginning.
我也希望時間能倒退  可現在已經這樣了
Well, I wish I could turn back time, but here we are.
你可以把我擋在亞特蘭大之外  想多久多久
And you can keep me out of Atlanta for as long as you want,
但你不能永遠拖著選票
but you can't hold the vote back forever.
時間在前進不是倒退  而時間站在我這邊
Time's moving forward, not back. And time is on my side.
如果希瑟·鄧巴想占總統不在的便宜
If Heather Dunbar wants to take advantage of the President's absence,
那是她的權利
that's her prerogative.
但是她仍在華府  也未發表公開聲明
But she's still in D.C., there's no public statement.
你認為這是占便宜
You see that as taking advantage?
你認為如果不是她在華府幕后操縱
You think Congresswoman Sharp would make calls on her behalf
夏普議員會代表她打電話拉票嗎
if she wasn't pulling the strings from Washington?
夏普說是她自己打的
Sharp says she's doing it on her own.
你沒有任何證據表明她們有合作
You don't have any proof of coordination.
你說得對  我沒有
You're right, I don't.
只是清楚人性  基本邏輯
Just human nature, basic logic,
而且比常人更了解
and a slightly better than average understanding
政治手腕
of political gamesmanship.
失陪一下  新聞發言人也要上廁所
Uh, if you will excuse me, even press secretaries have to pee.
-我馬上回來  -好的
- I'll just be right back. - Okay.
失陪  抱歉  失陪
Excuse me. Excuse me. I'm sorry. Excuse me.
怎么了
What's up?
莉安知道了  我認為是你告訴了她
LeAnn knows, and I think you told her.
對  直截了當  我全告訴她了
I did. Straight up. I told her everything.
-走  上樓去  -不
- Let's go. Upstairs. - No.
-你說什么  -鄧巴重回局內
- Excuse me? - You've got Dunbar in play,
杜蘭特和總統在一起
you got Durant with the President,
第一夫人在達拉斯
and the First Lady's in Dallas.
這里的一屋子記者
And I've got a room full of press
我從早上八點就在努力應付他們
that I've been keeping at bay since 8:00 this morning,
等我把熊孩子都哄睡了
so I will tell you why I told her...
再跟你講我為什么告訴她吧
after I tuck in all the children.
現在投票
Let's vote now!
請安靜一下
Order, please!
現在請希爾參議員講話
It is Senator Sheer's time to speak.
安靜
Order!
也許我們應該遂凱茜的愿
Maybe we should let Cathy have her way.
如果現在投票  你們獲勝  我們大選再戰
If the vote's held now, you two win. We focus on the general.
為什么這么說
What's brought all this on?
我只是在想我們這么做
I just wonder if we're in over our heads,
是不是不自量力  弗蘭西斯
Francis, trying to do this.
是因為你母親嗎
Is it your mother?
看到她病得這么重一定很不好受吧
I'm sure it's difficult to see her this sick.
她完全無助
She's completely helpless.
但我們并不無助  我們可以扭轉局勢
But we're not helpless. We can turn this around.
我想我只是...
I guess I'm just...
我不知道  也許我們做錯了
I don't know, maybe... maybe we're making a mistake.
也許我還沒準備好做你的競選搭檔
Maybe I'm not ready to be your running mate.
-康威有個四星將軍  -你母親快樂嗎
- Conway has a four-star general. - Is she happy, your mother?
不  她很痛苦
No, she's miserable.
湯姆逗她笑  但大多數時候不快樂
Tom makes her laugh, but mostly, no.
想象一下我肝衰竭了
Imagine my liver's failing.
-想象我要死了  -弗蘭西斯
- Imagine I'm dying. - Francis...
不  你就想象一下
No, I just want you to picture it for just a moment.
我躺在床上  像你母親現在一樣
There I am, lying in a bed just like your mother is now.
唯一能讓我高興的事
The only thing that would make me happy
就是知道我走了以后  你會接手
is to know that you would take over after I passed.
如果是凱茜
If it were Cathy...
我會和你母親一樣痛苦的
I'd be just as miserable as your mother is.
我會做好我的事
I'll do my part.
你就專注你的講話
You just concentrate on that speech.
好  謝謝你  弗蘭西斯
All right. Thank you, Francis.
晚安
Good night.
-她不吃東西嗎  -她吞咽很困難
- She, uh... she won't eat? - It's hard for her to swallow.
你覺得她還有多少時間
How much time do you think she has?
我說不準  可能是幾周
I can't be definitive, but... a couple of weeks, maybe.
如果她完全不進食  可能就只有幾天了
If she stops eating altogether, it could be days.
她很痛苦
She's in a lot of pain.
她可以不用這么痛苦
She doesn't have to be.
到了這一步  我們可以讓她舒適一些
When it gets to this point, we can make her comfortable.
舒適到讓她的身體不再掙扎
Comfortable enough that the body will let go.
那是她想要的嗎
Does she want that?
這個你該和你母親討論一下
That is something you should discuss with your mother.
我喜歡那些植物
I like the plants.
你放在那兒的那些
The plants you put in there.
小東西總能讓人眼前一亮  對吧
It's the little things, right?
如果我們干掉精煉廠
If we take out the refineries,
就能切斷他們的收入來源
that would eliminate their revenue stream.
沒有了資源  他們就無法進軍
They can't advance if they don't have the resources.
馬克宗總統明確表示
President Makhzun made it very clear
不希望精煉廠被毀
he wants those to remain intact.
從戰略角度看  那是我們最好的選擇
It's our best option from a strategic point of view.
傷亡最小  對他們能力的沖擊最大
Minimal loss of life, maximal impact on capability.
要么全面開戰  要么就不打
It's either total war or nothing at all.
這可不符合外交策略  凱茜
Well, that doesn't sound very diplomatic, Cathy.
我們要和恐怖分子談外交嗎
We're going to be diplomatic with terrorists?
我向馬克宗總統承諾過
I made a promise to President Makhzun.
你之前就違背過諾言  這次有什么不同
You've broken promises before. Why should this be any different?
不如我們休息一下  晚餐之后繼續吧
Why don't we break for dinner? We'll pick this up afterwards.
我想再考慮一下
I wanna review this a bit more.
我會讓人把食物送去羅斯福室
I'll have some food brought into the Roosevelt Room.
感謝各位
Thank you all very much.
凱茜  我們倆就在這里吃吧
Cathy, why don't you and I eat in here?
"要么全面開戰  要么就不打"
"Total war or nothing at all"?
如果我在鏡頭前說
The moment I get in front of those cameras
康威是對的  布洛哈特也是對的
and I tell them that Conway is right and Brockhart is right,
你把哈里發國的事完全搞砸了
and that you completely bungled the ICO situation,
你覺得鄧巴到時會怎么樣
how do you think Dunbar will do then?
請送兩份科布沙拉過來  謝謝
Can we get two Cobb salads in here, please?
-我不喜歡科布沙拉  -那你可以不吃
- I don't like Cobb salad. - Then you don't have to eat it.
謝謝你過來
Thanks for coming over.
我過來比你過去容易多了
Way easier coming here than you coming there.
我門外有十支新聞團隊守著呢
Must be ten news crews outside of my house.
你怎么跑出來的
How'd you escape?
老辦法  走后門
The old-fashioned way. Back door.
你怎么弄到我的住宅電話的
How did you get my home phone?
老辦法
Oh, old-fashioned way.
《先驅報》的聯絡簿
Rolodex from the Herald.
-跟我來  不會很久的  -好
- Come with me. I won't keep you long. - Yeah.
-這些花了你多少時間  -幾個月
- How long did this take you? - Couple of months.
我單獨做的
I've been working on my own.
我們有一整隊人手  都沒發現這個
We had a whole team and we didn't find this.
你們或許沒有深挖到貝茨城葡萄園
Well, you probably weren't digging as deep as the Bates City Vine.
沒有
No.
我們把大部分精力放在追蹤資金上了
We spent most of our energy tracking the money.
我們應該更關注出行記錄的
We should've been more focused on the travel logs.
我是和一個披薩店的人聊了之后才想到的
I wouldn't have checked either until I spoke with a pizza guy.
后來我想到  他們有可能篡改出行記錄
Then I realized they might be manipulating the logs.
于是你查到了拉尼根
Which gets you to Lanagin.
這還是不能證明他見了拉尼根
It still doesn't prove he met with Lanagin,
但我不知道車隊還能去哪
but I don't know where else that motorcade would've been heading.
你打算把這個公開嗎
Are you going public with this?
我是可以  但是他還能合理推諉
I could, but he has some plausible deniability.
全都推到密查姆身上
He pins it all on Meechum.
如果他掩蓋了行蹤
If he's covering up travel,
誰知道他還掩蓋了什么
who knows what else he's covering up?
那才是我想要的報道
That's the story I want,
而不是什么特勤局人員修改記錄
not some Secret Service man being loose with the books.
那你還沒有引起注意
So you're still under the radar.
我得請你對這一切保密
I have to ask you to keep all this to yourself.
我知道你現在有了機會  這很誘人
I know it can be tempting now that... you have a chance,
但如果這一切過早公布  他會提高警惕
but if this goes public too early, his guard goes up.
我退出選舉的時候很艱難
Listen, it was hard when I withdrew.
半數領導層和公眾都拋棄了我
How the leadership abandoned me, how the public did.
花了些時間
It took some time...
但我看開了
but I made my peace.
我是贏是輸本來就不好說
It's a crapshoot whether I can win this.
他可以反駁這樣的報道
He can probably fight that off.
你得寫一篇他無法反駁的報道
You need to write the story that he can't fight off.
你調查過他  突破點在哪里
You investigated him. Where's the weak link?
雷米·丹頓
Remy Danton.
那是湯姆弄的
Tom did that.
真遺憾  他會合適你的
It's a shame. He'd be good for you.
我從沒相信過牙仙
I never believed in the tooth fairy.
但你還是把錢拿走了
Well, you took the money anyway.
能幫我把那盞燈關了嗎  很刺眼
Could you turn off that light, please? Hurts my eyes.
你小時候  曾經
When you were small... you used to...
曾經求我  讓黑暗停止
used to ask me to make it stop, the dark.
你還記得嗎
Do you remember?
記得
Yes.
我向你保證我會的  早上就讓它停
And I promised you I would... in the morning.
但該死的  你會每天晚上
But, damn it, you would sit at that window...
坐在窗前
every night...
想憑自己的力量讓太陽升起來
trying to make the sun rise, all by yourself.
你臉靠在窗戶上睡著后
Your daddy would put you in bed...
你爸爸會把你抱上床
after you'd fallen asleep with your face against the glass.
我那時非常嫉妒
And I was so jealous.
嫉妒我和爸爸嗎
Of me and Daddy?
嫉妒你相信
That you believed.
你相信你可以讓太陽升起
You believed you could make the sun rise.
我跟護士談了  母親
I spoke to her, Mother, the nurse.
我做不到
I can't do it.
我做不到  母親
I can't do it, Mother.
我做不到你要我做的事
I can't do what you want me to do.
克萊爾
Claire...
你母親去世
it'd help you win...
會幫你贏的
having your mother gone.
為我做這件事
Do this for me.
讓我終于能
And let me be a help to you.
幫到你
Finally.
湯姆
Tom.
她想要你在場
She wants you to be there.
你想要什么呢
What do you want?
我也想要你在場
I want you to be there, too.
好了
Okay.
我告訴她是因為你讓我別無選擇
I told her because you put me in an impossible situation.
她沒有把柄  但你就是不聽
There's nothing on her, but you wouldn't listen.
那你來我家的時候肯定也沒聽進去
And you must not have listened when you came over to my house.
我說得很清楚
I was very clear.
那么  你又要把我丟到地上嗎
So... you're gonna throw me on the ground again?
看  這里有杯子  來吧
Look, here's a glass. Let's go ahead.
你要把我炒掉嗎
You wanna fire me?
好啊  不就是又有人辭職嗎
Fine. It's another resignation.
繼雷米  布洛哈特之后
After Remy, after Brockhart.
杜蘭特和鄧巴還虎視眈眈
With Durant, with Dunbar.
我是靠編故事謀生的
You know, I spin stories for a living.
我都形容不出這故事有多好拿來做文章
I can't begin to tell you how to spin this.
你開小冰箱可不是為了拿健怡可樂
You know, the minibar wasn't open because you wanted a Diet Coke.
我擔心你  道格
I'm worried about you, Doug.
我不需要人擔心
Nobody needs to worry about me.
你需要有人擔心你
Yeah, somebody does...
因為這個焦土政策對我們很不好
because this scorched-earth policy is bad for us.
我才不在乎莉安·哈維  我們需要她
I don't give a rat's ass about LeAnn Harvey. We need her.
而你需要我  但我們都需要你
And you need me. And we both need you.
-處在最佳狀態  -我很好
- At your best. - I'm fine.
是嗎  你不讓我控制損失
Are you? Instead of having me do damage control,
反而讓我傷害自己人
you're having me do damage to one of our own.
我是在保護總統
I am trying to protect the president.
而我是在保護你
And I'm trying to protect you...
免受自己的傷害
from yourself.
你別瞎說了  你才不在乎我
You're so full of shit. You don't care about me.
你干了那種事  我本該恨你
After what you did, I should hate you.
但那樣能給我們帶來什么呢
But where does it get us?
看一下《電訊報》吧
Check out the Telegraph.
策略起效了
The strategy is working...
如果你肯的話
if you let it.
或者逼我辭職  你決定
Or make me resign. Your call.
佩特羅夫:  杜蘭特不是救市和約旦河谷事件中的關鍵人物
安東尼·莫雷蒂紀念基金
捐款
道格拉斯·斯坦普
謝謝
您的5000美元捐款已收到
-你還好嗎  -那是她想要的
- Are you okay? - It's what she wanted.
我在問你
I was asking you.
把投票安排到明天
Schedule the vote for tomorrow.
我會飛回去在投票前講話
I'll fly back to speak just before.
克萊爾  你母親剛剛去世了
Claire, your mother just passed.
安排一下  弗蘭西斯
Schedule it, Francis.
湯姆寫了一篇講稿  很不錯
Tom wrote a speech. It's good.
-凱茜還沒同意  -那就逼她同意
- Cathy's not on board yet. - Then get her on board.
抱歉
I'm sorry.
-我不是...  -不不  沒關系
- I didn't mean to-- - No, no, it's all right.
我會搞定的
I'll get it done.
謝謝  明天見
Thank you. I'll see you tomorrow.
晚安
Good night.
讓杜蘭特國務卿去總統辦公室見我
Ask Secretary Durant to meet me in the Oval.
好的  先生
Yes, sir.
總統先生
Mr. President.
在咖啡桌上
Coffee table.
佩特羅夫:  杜蘭特不是救市和約旦河谷事件中的關鍵人物
有趣的是我都沒讓他這么做
The funny thing is I didn't even have to ask him to do it.
他自己做的
He did it on his own.
我尤其喜歡他說
I especially like where he says,
"凱瑟琳·杜蘭特堪用
"Catherine Durant is functional.
克萊爾·安德伍德強大"
Claire Underwood is formidable."
你看  時間沒有站在你那邊  而在我們這邊
So, you see, you don't even have time on your side. It's on ours.
到明天早上  會有十幾篇類似報道
By tomorrow morning, there'll be a dozen articles just like that.
所以你可以做選擇
So you have a choice.
你可以選擇在接下來四年中繼續當國務卿
You can redeem yourself as Secretary of State
重樹形象
over the next four years,
或選擇被世人銘記為  在中東辦砸了事
or go down in history as a fluke, who bungled the Middle East
在勃蘭登堡談不攏協議的沒用貨
and couldn't even close the deal in Brandenburg.
你有你的版本  我也有我的
You have your version. I have mine.
我相信我的版本會跟這個一樣引人注目
I'm sure mine will get just as much traction as this.
但是我的版本會贏  因為這個報道更有意思
But my version wins because it's the better story...
并且事情也確實如此
and it's also exactly how things went down.
你看連真相都不向著你
You see, you don't even have the truth going for you.
我不怕你
I'm not scared of you.
我背書鄧巴  會是一篇更好的報道
My endorsement of Dunbar, that makes for an even better story.
但你知道最棒的報道是什么嗎
But you wanna know what the best story is?
克萊爾的母親剛去世了
Claire's mother just died.
-我很遺憾  -我想你不是真心的
- I'm sorry to hear that. - Oh, I don't think you really are,
不過沒關系  反正全世界除了你都會難過
but that doesn't matter because the rest of the world will.
等她明晚做完講話
And by the time she gives her speech tomorrow night,
亞特蘭大乃至全國的觀眾
there won't be a dry eye in Atlanta
都會為之動容落淚
or across the rest of the country.
你可以保住你的工作  凱茜
So, you get to keep your job, Cathy,
只要以你代表的票為交換
in return for your delegates.
這個提議依然有效
That offer is still on the table.
我一直很忠誠  我幫你得到了這個位置
I have been loyal. I got you that table.
你想繼續守住  還是想拱手讓給康威
Do you wanna keep it, or do you wanna give it to Conway?
我在等移植手術的時候
You know, when I was waiting for my transplant,
我產生了特別逼真的幻覺  你都不會相信
I had the most vivid hallucinations. You wouldn't believe 'em.
你知道我看到誰了嗎
Do you know who I saw?
彼得·羅素和佐伊·巴恩斯  就在這個辦公室里
Peter Russo and Zoe Barnes, right here in this room.
佐伊就在這張沙發上引誘我
Zoe was trying to seduce me, right here on this couch,
而彼得把我的臉按在這塊玻璃上
and Peter, he shoved my face up against this glass.
香煙  剃須刀片和性愛
Cigarettes and razor blades and sex.
很可怕
It was terrifying.
我只想逃出這間
All I wanted to do was get out of this room
我費勁千辛萬苦才進來的房間
that I worked so hard to get in.
但它們陰魂不散是有道理的
But of course, it makes sense that they would've haunted me
因為全都是真的
because it's all true.
-什么是真的  -盧卡斯·古德溫所說的一切
- What is? - Everything Lucas Goodwin claimed.
我殺了他們兩個  就像他說的那樣
I killed them both, just like he said I did.
但當然沒人會相信  永遠不會有人相信
But of course, nobody believes it, and nobody ever will.
因為我們就是那么擅長
Because that's how good we are...
讓東西
at making things...
消失
disappear.
不  我們沒殺過人
No, we didn't kill anybody.
但如果需要
But we would have...
我們會的
if it was necessary.
你說得對  談判該結束了
So, you're right, the time for negotiations is over.
你要交出你的代表
You will hand over your delegates,
繼續在我的內閣任職
and you will serve on in my cabinet.
我們忘掉發生過的這一切
And we will forget that any of this ever happened.
因為如果你不照做
Because if you don't...
我向上帝發誓
I swear to God...
我永遠
I will never...
都不會忘記
ever forget.
現在你明白了嗎
Do you understand now?
明白
Yes.
好
Good.
我們去決定要怎么對付恐怖分子吧
Now, let's go decide what we're gonna do about these terrorists.
需要我給誰打電話嗎  做些安排
Want me to call someone? Make arrangements?
我們讓太陽升起來了
We made the sun rise.
這她也告訴你了
She told you that, too?
我們該動身了
We should get going.
我和漢娜想向第一夫人和總統
Me and Hannah want to extend our warmest condolences
致以最誠摯的哀悼
to the First Lady and the President.
我們為他們和伊麗莎白·黑爾的親人們祈禱
They and all of Elizabeth Hale's loved ones are in our prayers.
出于對離世之人的尊敬  今天我們不競選
And we won't be campaigning today out of respect for their loss.
愿上帝保佑總統夫婦
God bless President and Mrs. Underwood.
好了
Got it.
發布吧
Put it out.
她倒斃的時機掐得真好
Perfect timing... for her to drop dead.
我們本來正順風順水呢
We were on a roll, too.
我該準備講話了
I should prep for the speech.
我為你準備好了房間  我馬上就過去
I have a room set up for you. I'll be right in.
這邊請  安德伍德夫人
Right this way, Mrs. Underwood.
我讀過草稿了
I read the draft.
怎么樣
And?
-一個字都不用改  -我很高興你滿意
- I wouldn't change a thing. - I'm glad you're pleased.
我很高興你陪著她
I'm glad you were with her.
她很堅強  你很幸運
She's strong. You're a lucky man.
完全同意
Don't I know it.
女士們先生們  我很榮幸為大家介紹
Ladies and gentlemen, it is a great honor to introduce
國務卿凱瑟琳·杜蘭特
Secretary of State Catherine Durant.
謝謝  非常感謝大家
Thank you, thank you very much.
我知道大家和我一樣
I know that all of you join me
都對第一夫人親人的離世表示誠摯慰唁
in offering our sincere condolences to the First Lady for her loss.
今晚  我想向在代表大會上
Tonight, I want to offer my sincere gratitude
支持我的各位代表
to all the delegates who have honored me with their support
致以我最真摯的感謝
during the course of this convention.
我非常感謝你們
Thank you so much.
民主黨全國代表大會
國務卿杜蘭特
然而  經過深思熟慮
However, after much deliberation...
我決定  與辭職參加選舉相比  作為國務卿
I have decided that I have more to offer you as Secretary of State
我能更好地為大家服務
than to resign and run for office.
但我希望支持我的各位
But I want to encourage every one of you who has supported me
和我一起支持這位非凡的女性
to join me in supporting this extraordinary woman,
美國第一夫人  克萊爾·黑爾·安德伍德
the First Lady of the United States, Claire Hale Underwood.
我們愛克萊爾
謝謝
Thank you.
我們愛克萊爾
謝謝
Thank you.
晚上好
And good evening.
正如大家所知  我母親
As all of you know, my mother,
伊麗莎白·康斯坦斯·黑爾
Elizabeth Constance Hale,
久病后于昨晚去世
passed away last night after a long illness.
她是個堅強的女人...
She was a strong woman...
一個生猛的德州人
a fierce Texan...
從小...我和她關系就不好
We had... a difficult relationship from childhood onwards.
我們曾有過很長時間的疏離
At times, there were long periods of estrangement.
我們經常深深地傷害對方
We hurt each other... often and deeply.
如果說母親的病帶來了什么好事  那就是
If there was one good thing that came from my mother's illness...
讓我們有機會重新開始往來  撫平舊傷
it gave us a chance to reconnect, to mend old wounds.
人們并不是都能
And that's not an opportunity
在父母離世前有這樣的機會
people always get before a parent dies,
我很感激有這樣的機會
and I'm grateful to have had that.
那我在這里做什么呢
And what am I doing here?
我站在這里  是因為這是我母親所希望的
I'm here because my mother wanted me to be.
昨天在她去世之前  她對我說
Yesterday, before she passed, she said to me,
"克萊爾...去做吧
"Claire... do this.
如果這是人們希望的  聽他們的
If the people want it, listen to them.
如果失敗了  那就是失敗了
And if you lose, then you lose.
但是如果你贏了...
But if you win...
要感到榮幸  保持謙遜
be honored, be humbled,
和弗蘭西斯一起贏得選舉"
and win this election with Francis!"
我告訴她  康威夫婦是非常厲害的對手
And I told her, I said, "The Conways are tough opponents."
她說也許是吧  但也不比德州人
And she said, "They may be tough, but they're not Texas tough."
失去讓我們深思
Loss is a sobering phenomenon.
幾個月前  我差點失去了我丈夫
Several months ago, I almost lost my husband.
我們的國家差點失去了總統
Our nation almost lost a President.
失去讓我們重新審視我們珍惜的一切
Loss makes us reevaluate what we hold dear.
我還要告訴你們...
And I'll tell you, there were...
就在不久之前
times in the not too distant past,
弗蘭西斯和我...差點失去我們的婚姻
where Francis and I, we... almost lost our marriage.
我們遇到了困難  還以為堅持不下去了
Hard times when we thought we wouldn't make it.
正如很多人所知
And like many of you know,
婚姻并非總是一帆風順
marriage isn't always the smoothest road.
是一個精神錯亂的年輕人
And it took the actions of a deranged young man
讓我記起弗蘭西斯對我有多重要
to remind me how important Francis is to me.
現在  我母親去世了...
And now, with my mother gone...
他就是我唯一的親人了
he's the only family I have left.
我愿把我的人生  我們的國家和未來
I trust Francis Underwood with my life,
托付給弗蘭西斯·安德伍德
with our nation, with our future.
我希望你們也能信任他
I hope you will, too.
如果你們信任我們  我會謹遵母親的話
And if you trust the both of us, I'll heed my mother's words,
如被提名為他的競選搭檔  我將深感榮幸
and I'll be honored if you nominate me as his running mate.
我們愛克萊爾
克萊爾  克萊爾  克萊爾
Claire! Claire! Claire!
我們愛克萊爾
天吶  你真厲害
Jesus! You did great work.
女士們先生們...
Ladies and gentlemen...
秘書長女士  作為黨代會主席
Madam Secretary, as Convention Chair,
我提議通過口頭表決  對提名
I move that we make the nomination
克萊爾·安德伍德競選副總統
of Claire Underwood for Vice President...
弗蘭西斯·安德伍德競選總統做出表決
and Francis Underwood for President by acclamation.
對總統和副總統的提名
Do I hear a second to vote by acclamation
進行口頭表決  是否有人附議
for the nomination of the President and the Vice President?
-說得好  -提議通過
- Hear, hear! - So moved.
贊成提名
All of those in favor of the nomination
弗蘭斯西·安德伍德
of Francis Underwood for
競選美國總統的說贊成
President of the United States, say "Aye."
-贊成  -反對提名的
- Aye! - All those against.
反對
Nay!
贊成提名克萊爾·安德伍德
All those in favor of the nomination of Claire Underwood
競選美國副總統的說贊成
for our Vice President of the United States, say "Aye."
贊成
Aye!
-反對提名的  -反對
- Against? - Nay!
贊成者占多數
The Ayes have it!
本黨決定2016年總統選舉候選人
Our party's ticket for the 2016 Presidential Election
為弗蘭西斯和克萊爾·安德伍德
will be Francis and Claire Underwood!
民主黨全國代表大會
安德伍德夫婦獲民主黨提名